You came here to kill me.
From 80th The missing Niedermann
be regarded as extremely dangerous.
Exercise extreme caution.
Status of patrols?
81-20, switches.
81-20, can you hear me?
Switches.
Eight, one, two, zero.
Can you hear me? Switches.
She says
Lisbeth Salander.
She is 27 years.
In this issue we reveal --
- How the Swedish government officials
have conspired against her --
- To cover up a
pathologically ill murderer.
Alexander Zalachenko,
a detour from the Soviets.
In Sweden, he has done
guilty of serious crime:
Arms trafficking, drugs,
trafficking, maltreatment.
Alexander Zalachenko is
Lisbeth Salander father.
This number of Millennium
is dedicated to her resurrection.
Hello.
Can you open your eyes?
My name is Anders Jonasson.
I am doctor here.
You are at Sahlgrenska
hospital in Gothenburg.
Can you count to ten?
One, two, three...
It is good.
My text is on pages 40-50.
I will have parts of Björck
Investigation by facsimile.
To make it stronger, nicer.
- What have we of image material?
- Not much.
We can get pictures of Gunnar Björck,
Teleborian och Zalachenko.
- Some from St. Stephen's Hospital.
- Yes, and Lisbeth.
- It sounds like at least 75 pages.
- It may be more. It will be good.
- Can we find more names?
- No, we must focus on what we have.
We can hope that the publication
forcing others to light.
It takes one second, etc.
Now we work.
The news sends extra police after murder
Near Gosseberga this morning.
A massive police turnout is set
into the hunt for the perpetrator.
Police have identified him --
- As the 35-year German
Ronald Niedermann.
He is armed,
According to the police and very dangerous.
- I am looking Fredrik Clinton.
- Who can I bring greetings from?
Evert Gullberg, an old colleague.
Dad is sleeping, but got inside.
Zalachenko do what is best for him
whatever the consequences.
It is also my reputation.
We can not risk
he starts talking.
We need to silence him
at any price.
We agree.
It wont we be.
But you can see,
how I feel.
Fredrik, we need you.
One last time.
I can not.
I stay five hours --
- Every other day at the hospital
in a dialysis.
I die soon.
I can not get a new kidney.
How is it, my friend.
- Thank you.
- They are freshly baked.
I did not know you had a daughter.
No.
We do not so much
about each other's privacy.
Despite the fact that we have worked in...
... yes, more than 35 years.
What about Lisbeth Salander?
The case is already underway.
What do we do with her?
Hello Lisbeth.
How's it going?
Do you remember me?
Anders Jonasson.
It is understandable if you're tired.
You got shot in the head.
We managed to remove the ball.
It has not damaged any vital parts,
As we can see.
You also had gunshot wounds in
right shoulder and left hip.
But it seems that the entire fine.
What about brain damage?
They are complicated and can be
hard to see. What you will not mind.
The police will talk to you.
But I refused them access,
because of your condition.
They come back safely,
but I let them not come yet.
Liver Zalachenko?
He has patched together and stable.
But it's pretty bad.
Damn.
I was wondering
when you would come.
We have discussed how
we shall help you.
But to develop a strategy,
we must first hear your version.
How should the strategy look like?
We will come forward to
together.
But I think it'll hard to get
completely outside prison.
Gee, do you believe it?
We help with lawyer
and everything else.
But you must cooperate
and give us some guarantees.
Niedermann.
Niedermann is the culprit.
It was he
who shot Lisbeth.
There are suspicions against you,
which can be hard to get around.
It is your problem.
If you do not solve it --
- I contact the press.
I have the name,
dates, events - everything.
I can crush you completely.
I am a survivor.
It ought to know.
- Zalachenko you do not understand...
- It is you who do not understand!
This conversation is over.
Just one more thing.
Lisbeth...
- What is wrong with her?
- She must be overcome, understood?
Well. Well...
Hello. Excuse me for being late.
Then came my sister.
We are talking of.
- Is there no one at home?
- No.
However, Micke, she tried
to beat his father to death with an ax.
It's attempted murder.
Or self-defense.
But she is arrested for attempted murder
Zalachenko on, or what?
So, she needs a
criminal lawyer.
Lisbeth and her mother was exposed
for mishandel and abuse --
- Of Zalachenko and authorities.
It started long before Gosseberga.
Here's documents confirming it.
A copy of the investigation conducted
of one of Sapo, Gunnar Björck.
It proves how illegal block
a twelve-year girl lays on St. Stephen's --
- And the children of her.
Was it confidential?
Say you have it from a journalist
do not want to go out with, where he has it from.
You are willing to go far
for Lisbeth Salander, what?
Yes.
I do not need a lawyer.
You will be charged with attempted murder
your father.
Micke think they will try
to get you in to the closed again --
- So yes, you need a lawyer.
But you can choose another.
Unless you want an appointment.
Do I interpret your silence
as I need to go?
You decide.
Do you have a smoke?
- Does the nicotine patch?
- Yes, the moment.
I touched on 3rd room
Acute car soon?
I got this copy of Micke.
You know what it contains, is not it?
We will talk
a lot with each other.
So I want you to be completely
honest with me.
Micke told mostly
but some things he will --
- Have you even decide
if you want to tell.
I assume
you know what he thinks.
It is something with computers
and a DVD disc.
After everything we've done for you
through the years --
- Then you threaten us.
It is ventured.
I am a survivor.
I do what I think is necessary.
No, you do it because you are an evil
and through rotten man without honor.
Without morality.
I came here to give you our message.
We will not help you this time.
I have no choice.
Do not you understand that?
Life has taught me
that there always exists a choice.
Idiots.
- I crush you.
- You will not do anything.
No, get this.
I see what happens.
Out!
He has a gun!
What happens?
Fast!
Wait, I come.
Hold.
Hold on.
He pulled the door, but got
not opened it. It was so unreal.
An old beggar with the pistol.
Then I heard the shot
when he shot himself.
Are you sure that he tried
to get to Lisbeth?
Yes, it was awful!
I've never been so scared.
- Shall I come down?
- No.
You do not. I sleep with
Vera Åkerlund in Kålltorp.
- Press conference at the police station. 15.
- I'll have to run.
- Take care of yourself.
- Yes.
- We talk.
- Yes. Hello.
Why did the police not
better monitoring?
Absolutely unbelievable.
You would think no such thing can happen here.
To go armed into a department
and kill a patient is absolutely unbelievable.
Well... Fredrik?
What happens?
Come in, come.
We try to find information
about it now.
What time was it?
Find out.
What the hell?
- Do you know what happened?
- Zalachenko has been shot.
It would be Evert Gullberg
who shot him.
There is chaos there.
We have not had anything confirmed.
So I can confirm it.
It was Evert who shot him.
It was wrong.
- Should I get coffee or something?
- No, not now.
What the hell are you talking about?
What plans?
Gullberg had only a few months
left to live. He had liver cancer.
He chose to make a final
work for us.
He walked with honor intact.
- You knew he would kill him?
- Sure.
His task was to close
mouth Zalachenko.
And Salander, was the plan.
Are you equally away
by Gullberg?
Think about what you say, Hallberg.
It was the right decision.
- We did what was necessary.
- Necessary? Resolution?
You and Gullberg has no mandate
to make some decisions!
Whatever happens has Zalachenkos
death not related to us.
Nor Evert Gullberg.
Our task is to
make decisions --
- No one else dares.
Least of all politicians.
It's that simple.
One more thing...
I come back.
I'm looking the operational side --
- Until this crisis is over.
The man who fired the deadly
shot and later took his own life --
- Are identified
as a 78-year-old pensioner.
He has worked as
accountant and tax lawyer.
- What was his name?
- It informs us not at this time.
Is there a connection
Lisbeth Salander?
A possible connection to Lisbeth
Salander, we can certainly reject.
It seems to be about a lonely
perpetrator who acted --
- Based on an own
paranoid imagination.
He has sent confusing messages
to include famous politicians and media --
- Where there is death threats
v Alexander Zalachenko.
SÄPO analyzes it,
but the man was probably mentally ill.
It was everything from police
press conference.
We return to the incidents at
Sahlgrenska hospital in Gothenburg.
No!
- Challenge?
- Sure. Hamburger today.
- After you.
- Thank you.
Lisbeth?
- Need help?
- No thanks.
Eat your food properly.
I have a suggestion.
I do not run home.
I have rented a room.
Will you stay overnight?
I am completely finished.
I slept poorly, damn editor.
So we just sleep.
It is the fourth time
the car out there.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
- How would solve this?
- We could not foresee everything.
- Monitoring the hospital has increased.
- Thanks!
How in the hell would
in avoiding a trial now?
I do not think we can.
Locked doors and a psychiatric
assessment as to obstruct her up.
She must be punished for
attempted murder of Zalachenko.
And for the treatment of
it closed.
- And why not here at St. Stephen's?
- Yes.
If nothing else, for her sake.
What is the prosecutor?
Ekström.
Not a star, but ambitious.
We can handle him.
- And other copies of Björck exploration?
- We gather them in now.
It ought surely to cope.
You worry too much.
And it is blonde muskelbundt
who worked for Zalachenko?
- What happened to him?
- Ronald Niedermann.
He is on the run.
It's just a matter of time.
It is Lisbeth Salander half brother.
Zalachenko had an affair
with a woman in Hamburg.
It is kraftedme
as a Greek tragedy.
Zalachenko trying to shoot his daughter
while her brother helps.
Then she turns back from the dead --
- To smash an ax
the head of his father.
Yes, so you can choose to look at it.
You'll hear from me.
We talk, Vera. Hello.
Hey!
Can I get my bag back?
Give me your bag!
What the hell...!
On a moped stole your bag.
What? How are you?
Are you okay?
I'm fine. But Björck
investigation was in the bag.
It's okay. I make a copy.
Annika, I'll call you.
Milton Security Armanskij.
This is Mikael Blomkvist.
I need your help.
- What is the problem?
- I've had burglaries.
It can help.
Can I call from the office?
- Of course, call on your mobile.
- Fine, hey.
Charge against Lisbeth Salander
is not complicated.
Although Zalachenko is dead.
But if everything about Zalachenko comes out
it becomes a very bad trial.
It's about life,
our relationship with foreign nations --
- And SÄPO's
secret contacts.
I read well exploration
mostly as a background.
For the charge against Lisbeth Salander
it has no significance.
And now the RAW involved.
But parts of it are useful.
Especially to Lisbeth Salander
have tried to assassinate his father before.
I can see if you can get
access to the part.
Yes, it could benefit from.
So shall I,
you get it.
Who is your boss?
My orders come
from the very top.
This means that you can not
talk to anyone but me about this.
I'll be discreet.
- Anders Jonasson?
- Yes.
My name is
Peter Teleborian.
I am senior consultant at St. Stephen's
psychiatric clinic in Uppsala.
I need to talk to you.
It is about one of your patients
Lisbeth Salander.
- Yes?
- Yes... Okay.
I had to do with her
since she was twelve years --
- And has very good insight into
her disease picture.
- How does it look?
- Lisbeth is seriously mentally ill.
She has obvious delusions
with paranoid and schizophrenic features.
Like all sociopaths,
She is completely without empathy.
Quite simple.
I see her as closed
but not as paranoid sociopat.
She is extremely manipulative.
It is included in the disease picture.
She shows that she thinks you want to see.
As you understand, I hold great
concern for her mental condition.
I understand this.
I'll have to see her
to assess her condition before trial.
I can not help you.
I am responsible for Lisbeth.
She is not strong enough to
meeting other than his lawyer.
I have the court words
to be meeting her.
I had hoped to avoid being formal,
but I have to.
As a doctor you should know
that it is my assessment that apply --
- Whatever the law says.
So you must wait patiently for
me to change my decision.
I had hoped for a more
professional response.
Can we rule out
the government has been aware of?
They must have known that a Russian
spy is bolted to Sweden.
We had a socialist government in '76
since Zalachenko came.
30 years without something being leaked.
It had not been kept secret,
if a lot of politicians knew about it.
All writes biographies now.
It's the same with SÄPO.
It would be leaked.
It may be a small secret group
as acting entirely on their own.
With large resources
and influence.
If there are no leaks from
group in 30 years, how should we dig?
The best we have
Evert is Gullberg.
We find more of him
leads us perhaps more.
It should not take time
so Millennium is in trouble.
The newspaper must be out simultaneously
the trial.
Can you look at it?
- How do I feel?
- You are clearly improving.
I will ensure that you get help
to get started with training.
- I do not need help.
- I think so. Arrow does not hurt.
And you should eat better.
I should do something about the food.
- The food?
- Obtain a pizza or something.
I doubt
that there is pizza on the menu.
A dr. Peter Teleborian
would see you.
He said that the had
contact in the past.
He walked with a mission unfulfilled.
Well.
This was for you.
Hello. We were seen at the hospital the same night
by Lisbeth Salander came.
- I can remember.
- I will talk to you about something.
I will not disclose information
about Lisbeth Salander.
No, I will give you information
for Lisbeth. Important information.
Such a conspiracy. Sorry,
but it sounds very unlikely.
I can well understand that you think
but I assure you - everything is true.
Everything can be documented
and I publish the whole story.
I build Lisbeth defense for his trial.
That is why I am here.
- I would ask you one thing.
- What?
Lisbeth's secrets.
Private. As she can
need in his defense.
To arrive at the evidence
She needs this.
- The Prosecutor has deferred restrictions.
- So I ask you.
- Hey, how does it feel?
- Okay.
- Do I feel a little for you?
- Yes.
Let us look again...
- Are you hurt?
- No.
- What about headaches?
- Okay.
- The customer.
- Good.
Police from Stockholm
called again.
His Permanent was his now.
Introduced himself as exploration manager.
He would come and question you.
Can you bend your head slightly backwards?
Not too much. I was a little annoyed
than that they are so eager.
But I can not keep them go
with your medical condition much longer.
You start to get too quickly.
Do you understand?
I said that you need
a couple more weeks.
You will then be moved to
jail in Stockholm.
I saw your tattoo on her back.
It seems quite large.
- Why did you get it done?
- Why ask?
- Pure curiosity.
- Private reasons I will not mention.
Okay. Sorry.
It must have hurt
and have taken time.
Yes, it was both hurt
and took time.
Sorry.
Hello Lisbeth. With this you can tell
your version of what happened.
Your autobiography.
Annika do not know that you have your
lommepc and it is she does not.
Should I give her the DVD?
We also need to know more
on Teleborian.
I live in your apartment.
Mine is monitored and intercepted enough.
Murder Suspects Lisbeth Salander
moved from the Sahlgrenska in Gothenburg --
- Arrest of Kronoberg in Stockholm
As soon as her condition allows.
It informs the police press spokesman.
The trial is scheduled
to the beginning of November this year.
Plague, are you there?
Okay to give the DVD to Annika,
but I write even though the rape.
Plague has been contacted about Teleborian.
He will contact you
if he finds something.
I have links to the government.
Guess who visited the Prime Minister
5 October 1976?
A Evert Gullberg and a named
Hans von Rotting.
They were there three weeks after
that Zalachenko bolted.
- How did you find out?
- I checked the visitors.
There was only one visit
5 October 1976.
Well done, Christer.
But it must be proved that they were
to inform about Zalachenko.
- Were there any notes?
- No, just the name and date.
- How do we proceed?
- We drive to the Secretaries.
- Two working there may know something.
- Do we have some names?
One is dead and the other is
Retired ambassador.
His name is Bang Janeryd
and live outside Grisslehamn.
- We should have a chat with him.
- Good. The agents I know.
I have more control over the material
and more dangerous for him.
- It's just what I say.
- Yes, I hear...
Address?
Yes.
Fucking well done.
You must have understood that Gullberg
Zalachenko shot or what?
- You read the newspapers?
- Yes.
- Why did you not to the police?
- I expected that they would call.
- It sounds a little convenient.
- I knew nothing about her daughter.
That she was subjected to
is terrible.
But the prime minister was not aware of it.
Neither do I.
You must convince me
and Millennium readers about it.
I forbid you to use
my name in this context.
I have not had anything to do with it.
What I read here is new to me.
You have only read part of it.
We have a lot more.
Anything can be proved.
I will not hang you out,
but you have a responsibility and a debt.
So either tell you this now,
or save you behind your confidentiality.
- I call it extortion.
- Call it what you want.
Are you talking, so I promise,
not to mention your name.
The prime minister had contact with
Evert Gullberg and Hans von Rotting.
- Did you also contact them?
- Yes.
There was one more, Clinton.
As the American president.
- Clinton?
- Yes.
How often met in?
A ten times during my time.
I got nothing to know.
Just Zalachenko cooperated --
- And that information
was invaluable.
Who took the switch?
I do not know.
- You are not handed to anyone?
- No.
And the parade does not report?
No, everything was of course top secret.
I had not even
take notes during meetings.
So, no subsequent government
had an idea --
- The existence of a Soviet
detour in Sweden?
It sounds strange,
but it may be so.
- What is it?
- We have a problem.
I have checked Teleborians Hard
mail and found nothing.
- Nothing?
- Nothing about you or trial.
The only thing that could be something
are two short emails from...
... Jonas hotmail.
"PSU 1 ready next week."
It is from September 20 this year.
The second is equally brief:
"PSU 2 ready tomorrow."
PSU? Psychiatric opinion?
Yes, it could be.
- No files?
- No.
He has not sent anything
from its arbejdspc.
He must have a laptop
with mobile broadband.
- It may be hard to get in.
- But not impossible?
Nothing is impossible.
- I keep an eye on his inbox.
- Do it. But the ring no more.
- SMS or email.
- Okay, bye.
Damn!
Hello, Mikael Blomkvist.
Monica Figuerola.
- Yes?
- I would invite to a talk.
It is a friendly invitation.
You risk nothing.
- Can I retrieve mail?
- Yes.
- And a pair of clean underpants?
- Absolutely.
Torsten Edklinth.
- Blomkvist.
- After you sit.
You are probably aware
why we want to meet you.
So let's get down to business.
We have confirmed the existence
a secret group, a conspiracy --
- Within a very sensitive part
of state administration.
My meeting with the Prime Minister last night
resulting in a full investigation.
Which means...?
A full investigation.
The result is given to prosecutor
assessing whether to indictment.
But we need time to identify
who are involved.
I understand this.
Where do I sign?
We will know when you intend to print.
It happens before the investigation is over,
it can put it all on games.
When seems that I should press?
We can not determine.
It provides, you have complete
but I ask that you cooperate.
Let me say this...
I am pissed mad at the state,
Government SÄPO --
- And all the other fuck heads who
blocked a twelve-year girl inside --
- For no reason, in mental hospital
and get her incapacitated adults.
I myself am very shocked
what happened with Lisbeth Salander.
But those responsible are punished.
Until then, we must identify
who is involved.
I will also.
But I also want Lisbeth Salander
acquitted and the authorities made in court.
It can neither we nor
government stand against.
Assuming
I'll get insight into the investigation --
- So tell me what
I press and when.
Information to the information.
It can be solved very simply.
We decide which employees
which we include in the investigation.
We can recruit Mikael Blomkvist
as an external consultant.
Evert Gullberg.
Do you have any more names?
Hans von Rotting, Frederick Clinton.
One is dead, the other is retired.
- Both active in the group in '70 and '80s.
- Group?
Can we give it a name?
We call on the subject.
Section?
Clear.
How did you find it?
I have a good source.
- Can we keep this place?
- It provides for me.
I was clamped in bed.
Peter Teleborian stood by the bed.
He smelled of aftershave.
I hated his smell.
I heard his breathing change
and saw his mouth move.
But I did not
what he said.
I hated his mouth.
It was the night I was 13 years.
Niedermann is your brother.
Come on, Buster, search!
- Yes, search.
- 80-1651, arrived.
Come in, 1651.
We have searched the lower level.
It is empty.
Committed burglary in the house
next door, but police are here.
Want something to sleep on?
Lisbeth tried several times
to tell the social services --
- On Zalachenkos abuse
of her mother --
- But nobody took the ten-year girl
accusations seriously.
To save his mother tried
Lisbeth finally decided to kill his father --
- By throwing a milk carton
with gasoline in his face --
- And then a burning
match.
Then society reacted.
But not by punishing
Alexander Zalachenko.
Instead, Lisbeth punished.
Twelve years old, she was locked
at St. Stephen's in Uppsala.
When she came out she was incapacitated adults
and placed in custody.
It's me.
Teleborian meet with Jonas
16 o'clock at Center.
- What time is it?
- Soon half.
Damn!
- Hello. I'll take some blood tests.
- I just need the toilet.
- Yes, Christer.
- I'm in the middle of the staircase.
Yes, I see you now.
I'm just below.
I'm Teleborian the ring.
Christer, go ahead. I will stop here.
Okay.
You should see him soon.
Black jacket.
I see him now.
He stands there and waits.
- Watch him, not too close.
- No, I'm watching.
Someone is coming.
It must be Jonah.
Gray jacket older.
Can not recognize him.
- Now they go. Should I follow.
- Yes, follow your after!
- They go against Vasagatan.
- Follow along.
Mikael here. Teleborian have a meeting
with a working of the Section.
- Okay, where at?
- At Vasagatan. Do you?
Okay. Yes, I come.
- Hello.
They are there.
- Mikael.
- You go now.
Follow Teleborian.
We follow the second.
Monica here.
I need information on a car.
Guess who went through it
four hours ago.
Frederick Clinton.
- Teleborians opinion?
- A draft.
It must be machined,
but it looks good.
Teleborian yesterday from a meeting
with Jonas Sandberg from Section --
- To a meeting at Police Headquarters?
- With whom?
- We will see.
Jonas Sandberg joined SAK 1998th
To counterintelligence.
2001 he was transferred
to a secret location abroad.
He should be at the embassy in Madrid
but they have never heard of him.
Here is the section's properties.
23 flats, six storeys.
I have checked all tenants
but nothing unusual.
Beyond here, the flat top.
11 rooms and kitchen.
It is owned by the company Bellona.
The owners live abroad.
- Can we get a camera up?
- Do we have a warrant?
The clear, I
If you obtain a teapot.
Never mind, I take one home.
- Hello.
- Am I disturbing you?
- Yes.
- I come back.
- I know little about.
I just want to warn
the police come tomorrow.
Okay.
I would drag the move
a couple of days, but...
- My colleagues would wonder.
- That you should not.
- Safe?
- Yes.
- You do not seem worried.
- No.
I have a gift for you.
Why?
You have been one of my most
entertaining patients long.
If you're bored in jail.
Latest within DNA research.
- Your mobile...
- In the chocolate box.
Teleborian writes a
expert opinion.
How he comes forward to you
need treatment at the closed.
Prosecutor demands.
But we hire one's own expert
which comes with its own opinion.
Lisbeth, this is for your own good.
I do not talk to any brain-bending.
I have already said.
Hope they fit.
The one who loses the
the setting is yourself.
But Lisbeth...
- Move you.
- Lisbeth Salander...
- How are you, Salander?
- Lisbeth...
Do you have any comments?
Murder Suspects Lisbeth Salander
was today moved with police escorts --
- From Sahlgrenska in Gothenburg
the Kronoberg jail in Stockholm.
According to prosecutor Richard Ekstrom
the trial --
- Scheduled for 6 November.
Lisbeth Salander is sighted --
- The attempted murder of his father,
Alexander Zalachenko --
- Who later brutally murdered
at Sahlgrenska Hospital.
There are increased security
in connection with the trial --
- After there has been threats
during the police investigation.
- Sonny? When the hell did you come out?
- This morning.
- What about Magge?
- He is a little longer.
Good to see you.
The police conducted a search
same day were taken.
They found nothing. Later came the blonde
Satan and wanted a hideaway.
Magges and your mate.
He is not fucking my buddy.
He is wanted in the whole country.
Therefore, he needed a hideout.
I sent him home to Viktor.
Sonny!
What the hell?
Jenny... Jenny!
Jenny!
Jenny? It's me, Sonny.
Who was it?
Nieder...
Niedermann.
Viktor Viktor...
Niedermann...
He should fucking die for this.
"Lisbeth Salander autobiography"?
- Can anyone prove it is stated?
- Impossible. They have no proof.
Blomkvist is not stupid.
It's Erika Berger did not.
We must go in-depth approach
to get them.
Press the green.
We do not have much time.
We must put the pressure up.
- If the trip is today?
- It's Malins, right?
Hello. How's it going?
- Is it okay with sushi?
- Not fish. Chicken teriyaki to me.
- Do you have lunch, Mick?
- No, I do not have time.
Okay. Erika eight bites?
Can I change the battery with you?
Mine is flat.
Micke... View.
It is an anonymous.
I think it is the same as last.
- Have you had many?
- I got one last week.
- Why did not you say something?
- I did not take it seriously.
It is between us,
As we talk more later.
- Do I take it?
- Take it.
- Will you have eight pieces?
- I am not as hungry today.
I hope so.
You need to give evidence.
So we finally meet.
Ekström, prosecutor.
We may well see this initial meeting
as a conversation rather than an interrogation.
One way to get a little track
on the complicated story.
I assume
you do not have anything against it.
Charges against you are serious.
But as the prosecutor should I take into account
to all mitigating circumstances.
It is important that you are aware,
for your own sake.
This is a simple question.
Answer yes or no.
When you went to Gosseberga
to meet daddy --
- Had you already as plans
to kill him?
So I must ask the lawyer again
try getting Salander to respond.
So I must repeat that my client
even decide if she will respond.
I ask the lawyer to take
a serious talk with Miss Salander.
I say this for her sake.
Yes...
I was surprised that she was
so small and slender as a girl.
The trial starts on 13
When should the newspaper be ready.
We must press the week before.
- How is it done?
- We must help each other.
You and Malin writes about Teleborians
background and a little about St. Stephen's.
Approximately 30 pages. Is it okay?
- Yes, I suppose it's okay.
- Good.
Yes...
Then there was another thing.
I have received two anonymous emails --
- The past week
who should know.
Threat Mail?
Fy for hell.
Who the hell sent this?
- Do we have declared it?
- I do not want the police here.
It is a serious threat to Erika.
We take it just as seriously. I would
have no police at the editors.
- Shall we just shit on it?
- It's not what I say.
- I carry it in my own way.
- How?
Police shit on that.
They do not a damn thing!
Stop now!
I get no more, no
happened. Let it go.
- Next item.
- 30 pages?
- How has Lisbeth Salander it?
- Well, under the circumstances.
- What do you say to accusations?
- No comment.
You gotta defend her
and must surely say something.
Hello. Sitting in here?
Sorry to be late.
Good to have eaten at.
It is here to enjoy.
It is Lisbeth autobiography.
What? When she wrote it?
It does not matter.
"Bjurman"?
Lisbeth is the guardian?
- What is this?
- It's a movie.
You may even see.
Lisbeth approved to serve
in court if you need it.
Want?
- Is Lisbeth Salander fresh now?
- It is estimated that she may be heard.
- So she is physically well.
- But not mentally, or?
It is known that Lisbeth Salander
for several years has been treated in mental hospital.
You think that Lisbeth Salander
still is mentally ill?
The diagnosis can not I ask.
I have sought psychiatric
investigation to get answers.
- What is the doctor?
- Peter Teleborian.
He is chief psychiatrist
at St. Stephen's.
Peter Teleborian,
what a surprise.
Christer?
- Is it the same sender?
-Yes.
"It gets worse now.
For all of you. "
Is it us?
- How Micke trying to trace the sender?
- He called one.
It has not helped.
We must declare it.
- We can not wait to fall shots.
- I will talk to Michael first.
- So call me.
- No. I am responsible publisher.
And I've got mail.
I am not behind Michael's back.
We must stick together.
Agree. Especially now.
I'll call Michael.
Mikael Blomkvist. I can not
take it, but leave a message.
Micke, where the hell are you?
I've still got a mail --
- Now it's not just about me.
It feels fucking uncomfortable.
Call back!
Hello, Lisbeth.
You should know that I am sorry
that you have come to this situation.
I'll try to help you
in all possible ways.
I hope that we can
cooperation, you and me.
I think we taught each other
pretty good to know.
During that time.
You were a stubborn --
- And unusually severe treatment
twelve years.
You bit my finger again.
Can you remember?
You could never understand that contact
can be a part of the treatment --
- Which creates proximity and
confidentiality.
This applies especially children.
Do you realize that I am the person --
- Which has the greatest opportunity
to help you?
Do you?
- Hello. Are you still there?
- I called several times.
I wrote and had extinguished it.
Same sender.
Christer tried to report it.
But I stopped him.
We need it resolved now, Mikael.
You and I are running the newspaper.
We have a responsibility towards its employees.
This is not just the two of us anymore.
I have had contact with one of Lisbeth
hacker friends, Plague.
So they need no
police?
If anyone can find the sender
it is him, but it takes time.
It goes faster than the police.
We're talking days? Or weeks?
Frankly,
so I do not know.
If we assume
Millennium to have something to publish --
- What can they have?
The worst is probably that
they have a copy of Björck investigation.
But they may not know anything
about our company.
But he has high credibility.
It's also the newspaper.
We can perhaps lower
the credibility of a way?
Whatever...
We have to put an end to this,
once and for all.
She phoned
quarter past three in the night.
She had locked themselves away
in a room upstairs.
- We were there 20 minutes later.
- Have some tracks?
The police are doing.
We install alarms in the house.
Erika told of mail.
It is enough with
what happened last night.
My contact is trying to track them.
I would not confuse the police into it.
It is time now. It's about
physical threats against you and Erika.
- Towards me?
- Yes, even against you.
Your silent alarm in the apartment
went last night.
He was in 17 minutes.
When we searched the apartment --
- We found 180 grams of cocaine
stored in one of your speakers --
- And 120,000 dollars in cash
in gaderoben.
- What the hell?
- They try to hit you.
Now if they can not hit the newspaper.
- Is it still there?
- The money is.
The second is switched off.
- I'll have to call Erika.
- I think she's asleep.
- Erika.
- It's me.
I know what happened.
- I want to be seen. Can I come?
- No, you do not come here.
We must talk about it later.
- I want to be seen now.
- I would sleep a few hours.
At three o'clock?
Samir Gryta?
- Will you or will you not?
- At three o'clock. I come.
- Good. Hello.
- Hello.
I'll take these three pages to the printer.
Have we not heard from Erika?
I've talked to her. She had the
bad last night and would sleep in today.
- How is she now then?
- Better. Damn, I need to go.
Has she got more mail?
We have really made a cannon work
with this number all together.
- Are you in and have a pils later?
- No, I have a meeting at Samir.
There is an uncertainty
how several of these individuals --
- Linked to
Section's activities.
There may be several
we do not yet know.
The key persons, we have identified
and they will be arrested in a major action.
More information about this later.
It is ten minutes in three. We pause,
and gather here again in an hour.
- Has there been anything today?
- Clinton has been receiving dialysis.
The other has come and gone.
Jonas Sandberg is probably the
only there have been social.
Kl. 10:30, he met with two
people at a pizzeria in Bredäng.
- Who did he?
- The new faces for me.
- Just like Balkans.
- The brothers Nikolic.
Tomi and Miro Nikolic. From Serbia,
but they have lived in Huddinge.
Very unpleasant types.
Sharpshooters in the Civil War.
Miro wanted for mishandel,
but they live mostly in Serbia, so...
Mikael...
Hello, Samir.
Sorry to be late.
- How are you?
- How do you think?
- Why did you not?
- What could you have done?
I called Milton Security
because I needed help.
We back now, Micke.
Samir Gryta on Söder.
Connect me quickly, please.
I stopped the newspaper.
I called the printer.
This also applies to Malin and Christer.
Their safety.
- Did you call the print shop?
- I do not take the responsibility.
- It's too dangerous.
- Hell...
- Mick, who is the phone.
- No, not now.
It is important.
Sorry.
Down!
- They shoot!
- We take a shortcut.
What the hell!
Down!
Police! Police!
Show your hands!
Now!
Police! Show your hands!
How are you?
Are you okay?
- Here, if you will dry up.
- How are you?
Get Blomkvist and Berger
into a goddamn speed.
We go out through the kitchen.
The kitchen!
Both officers were
eat at the restaurant --
- And recognized her brothers, whom
one was called.
Exchange of fire broke out as they
were arrested, but no one was hurt.
The two brothers are now suspected
for attempted murder.
It is something damn shit.
Damn!
I chatted with Christer and Malin.
- They can not be on the editorial board now.
- No...
We could also have been killed today.
Both.
There is no job
worth dying for.
No.
We do not know if they just would kill you
Mikael, or Erika.
But the idea was that the police
would find drugs and money --
- And associate it with a
Yugoslavian drug showdown.
- The other of the editors?
- We close a couple of days.
We postpone the newspaper.
So I suggest that protection
to you and Erika.
No, I will not have any.
- We must see how it goes.
- Have you had contact with her?
What happens?
I will push to Lisbeth Salander
a behandlingsdom --
- The second priority,
a long prison sentence.
Tends not to be reversed?
Yes, but in this case --
- Is the psychiatric opinion
so unequivocal --
- I have no alternative.
Thank you very much.
The trial of Lisbeth Salander
starts here in Stockholm City Court --
- At noon today. 13, about an hour.
It is expected to take place in three days,
and interest is high, as in looks.
Police and prosecutor have
investigations --
- Information given to the media while
defense has denied...
Holy shit.
Is it time?
- I did not sleep one hour last night.
- It'll go well.
Of course...!
It seems to go well.
- So.
- Thank you. See you later.
A little more, little more.
I can only regret --
- To Lisbeth Salander did not say
a single word during interrogations.
The fact does not
charges weaker.
Thank you.
So I leave the floor to the lawyer.
From the defense side,
we reject all counts.
We will prove that
prosecutor's allegations are wrong --
- And that my client has been exposed
for serious legal violations.
I will ask my client
found innocent --
- That her guardianship repealed
and that she be released immediately.
Thank you.
Prosecutor has anything to add?
I desire that the negotiations
happens behind closed doors.
It's about a man's face
psychological health and wellbeing --
- And on material which
confidential --
- And in some parts may come
to affect national security.
We are talking tonight.
Well.
So we must begin by
try to get some clarity --
- Why you ran to Gosseberga --
- To try to assassinate your father,
Alexander Zalachenko.
Should we understand your silence,
as you will not answer questions?
I answer like questions.
Maybe you can answer
questions.
I have not seen anything
I asked if you drove to Gosseberga
aware that you would kill your father.
No, you said you would try
To get some clarity --
- So I drove to Gosseberga
to try to kill my dad.
It was an allegation.
- Answer the question.
- No.
- No, what?
- If the answer to the question.
You found a hatchet in the head of your father?
Yes.
He got seriously hurt, and I argue
it is attempted murder.
How do you feel?
It was two allegations.
What should I have an opinion on?
About hatchet blow to the head of your father
was attempted murder.
It was not attempted murder.
It was self defense.
Thank you.
Tell if you need anything.
- Can you get cigarettes?
- Forget it.
Thank you.
- Hello.
- How does it feel to be monitored?
- It's probably okay.
As long as they stay outside.
Erika...
I could not do it.
You are an egoist.
And idiot.
I will be home this week.
And next week.
I must be sure
it is the right decision.
Yes...
It is about us
or Millennium?
Both and.
I think.
You'll hear from me.
Take care of yourself.
Damn.
Salander, it's time.
Lisbeth Salander
so-called autobiography --
- Miss al
credibility.
It is a series of allegations
on different people --
- One more absurd
than the other.
Everything is an expression of --
- The paranoid schizophrenia
Lisbeth Salander who is suffering from.
Can you give an example?
The most obvious
is the portrayal of rape --
- As she claims --
- That her guardian, lawyer
Bjurman guilty in.
Full story
with all the details --
- Is a classic example
on the kind of grotesque fantasies --
- As children take on.
Now is Lisbeth Salander is not a child
she is an adult woman.
We're not held --
- At what level of mental
she is.
But in principle you're right.
I understand.
In 1993, Lisbeth Salander
forced hospitalized at St. Stephen's.
The years she lived there,
you had the responsibility for her.
- Is it true?
- Yes.
How many days she lay belt?
So fastened in bed.
I can remember impossible.
Not very many.
Approximately?
Possibly one thirty pieces.
I do not understand what that has to do with the.
Lisbeth Salander himself, claiming
it was 381 days.
It is pure fantasy.
It is quite unreasonable.
She was therefore not clamped
Having more than one year...
-... Of the two years she lived there?
- Of course not.
The defense has repeatedly tried
get Lisbeth Salander journal --
- From the years she was hospitalized
St. Stephen's, but without success.
- Can you explain why?
- Yes, it is confidential.
It is these studies generally.
The lawyer should know.
Here I have a copy of Lisbeth
Salander records from the two years --
- 1993 and 1994.
Here it is clear that Lisbeth
Salander was clamped in 381 days.
Attorney Giannini,
what does it matter to do?
I want to prove that Peter Teleborian
not telling the truth in the situation.
Attorney Giannini, records from
'93 And '94 can not be used today --
- To ask questions at
Peter Teleborians credibility.
I understand.
I felt like an idiot.
When the prosecutor presents Teleborians
new opinion, I have nothing.
She ends up at the closed again
and I can not do a damn thing.
Welcome to
your own girls.
Who are you?
Plague.
What is this?
Peter Teleborians private PC.
A USB copy.
Sorry. Come.
What's in it?
Everything you need.
Plus some nasty shit.
Annika, I have it all here.
Cooperation with the subject.
The psychiatric opinion
in several versions, false datings --
- Email correspondence, too.
Yes, there you are. It was good.
- Here.
- That when I never read.
Read it over lunch.
The dates are important.
Well, damn good.
See you later. Hey hey.
You ended up at St. Stephen's --
- After having poured petrol
your father and ignited it.
- Yes.
- Why did you do that?
Because he had abused my
mother for several years.
12. June 1993, he abused her
so brutally that she was disabled.
- She got permanent brain damage.
- Did you tell it to anyone?
Yes, the police who interrogated me --
- To the social worker, different doctors,
a priest and the pig.
When I came to St. Stephen's
I tried to explain what had happened.
But he claimed that I fantasized.
As punishment, I was clamped.
It is nonsense.
Another example of --
- That your client lacks the ability
to separate fantasy from reality.
- You lie, your fucking pig.
- Here we are talking properly.
Now I will go ahead
with the sexual assault --
- As a lawyer Bjurman
exposed my client.
It is not the case.
It is absurd allegations
without any hint of proof.
It is an example of the judicial
assault by Lisbeth has been exposed.
When it comes to Frederick Clinton
he may be to dialysis.
In the case of
Karolinska Hospital.
I get all the files
with all the information.
I repeat.
Group 1: Bublanski.
Group 2: Svensson.
Group 3: Bold.
Group 4: Figuerola.
Group 5: Holmberg.
For questions or ambiguities
then contact you to your respective leader.
Good luck.
So you claim that the lawyer Nils
Bjurman have raped you?
- When was it in which case have happened?
- Not "in which case".
It happened Tuesday
18 February 2008 --
- And Friday the 7th March of that year.
It is clearly in my biography.
- Reviewed you get them?
- No.
- Why not?
- Police have never listened.
Did you doctor for the damage?
No.
- You Talked to someone about it?
- No.
Deceased lawyer Nils Bjurman
has never been convicted.
He has never been notified
or been under investigation.
However, it is my job
to remind you that Lisbeth Salander --
- Have been diagnosed
paranoid schizophrenic.
She has spent several years
on child psychiatric clinic --
- And has been incapacitated adults
since the eighteenth year.
How regrettable it may be
then it's his land.
Lisbeth Salander has its
very own worldview.
It shows very clearly
In this autobiography.
No one else appears to her
rupture of realism so clearly.
In light of the --
- We must try to assess the credibility
in her words and statements.
- Is the prosecutor finished?
- Yes.
Then the lawyer present
his evidence.
Peter Teleborian claims
Lisbeth Salander to lie --
- On allegations that she has been
sexually exploited by lawyers Bjurman.
The prosecutor takes the same view.
I must now demonstrate that it
by Lisbeth told is completely true.
When was this filmed, Lisbeth?
On 7 March 2008.
I used a hidden camera.
If you are sweet...
If you...
... I'm also sweet.
Are you sweet?
Are you sweet? Are you sweet?
It is too late.
Stop the film!
That's enough!
- Why you filmed it?
- Bjurman had raped me before.
He had forced me to oral sex.
He called for more to
I had to get my money.
It was the only way
to obtain evidence against him.
Only way to stop him.
We take a break.
An hour's break.
- Sorry I come too late.
- It's okay. Thank you.
Presents lawyer new acts?
It is the same as the law already,
but with small crucial differences.
I come to it.
- Then I give the floor to the lawyer.
- Thank you.
Yes...
Nobody can deny
that Lisbeth was postponed --
- For serious sexual assault of
her guardian, lawyer Nils Bjurman.
A person she thought
that she could trust.
As I have said, illustrates this
a type of assault against Lisbeth.
The attacks have been both
psychological and legal.
The person who bears a major responsibility
this is dr. Peter Teleborian.
He has, in 1993 with Gunnar Björck --
- Which is part of an illegal
group inside SÄPO --
- Write a legal psychiatric
opinion --
- Which ensures that
confine a dangerous witness --
- So Lisbeth Salander,
on a closed psychiatric clinic.
There must be some way
which these accusations...
Excuse me, but now I speak.
This occurred after
Lisbeth had poured gasoline on his father --
- Alexander Zalachenko, in a
desperate attempt to save the mother.
But they are protected Zalachenko --
- Made sure to put a lid on it
and make confidential investigations.
In place was taken
Peter Teleborians help --
- To confine Lisbeth
at St. Stephen's in Uppsala.
It's a crazy accusation!
I have tried to help Lisbeth
Salander in all ways. She tried...
Yesterday preferred Peter Teleborian here
its new legal psychiatric opinion.
Once again, it proposes --
- The compulsory detention Lisbeth Salander
and locking her up.
But, as in 1993,
is it under false pretenses.
That is quite...
I must ask you to allow the lawyer
speech finished, thanks!
Thank you.
This opinion is based on
observations of my client.
These should have happened from the time she was
moved to Kronobergsarresten --
- 6 October, and should be
completed on 5 November.
Is it true
Peter Teleborian?
I will call two witnesses.
No!
The police, drop the weapon!
Yes... Do you know the document?
Yes.
It is the psychiatric opinion on
Lisbeth Salander by Peter Teleborian.
It comes in three versions.
The first, dated 20th September,
the second on 1 October --
- And this is the third,
which is dated 6th October.
You gave me the documents.
And I have noted that the first
opinion 1st October --
- Identical to the opinion
by Peter Teleborian preferred yesterday.
Dated 5 November.
Very odd.
Peter Teleborian has written
opinions --
- Before he met Lisbeth Salander.
Thus it lacks credibility.
Edklinth, it is true --
- That you have these statements
about Salander by Mikael Blomkvist.
Yes.
- What is your conclusion?
- They are false.
They were written long before --
- Peter Teleborian had the opportunity
to meet Lisbeth Salander in jail.
They are also produced in collaboration
with Jonas Sandberg.
It is a lie.
- Is it a lie?
- No, not at all.
The documents are dated
and there are email correspondence --
- Between Peter and Teleborian
Jonas Sandberg proving this.
He is part of a clandestine group inside
Sapo, which since the 70 --
- Has protected
Alexander Zalachenko.
The group was behind
Decision --
- To confine Lisbeth Salander
at St. Stephen's in 1993.
Jonas Sandberg is a
out of a few handfuls of people --
- Who is now arrested.
He is suspected of aiding
the murder of Gunnar Björck --
- And possibly more murder.
We have evidence.
Will Peter Teleborian
comment on this?
Two policemen waiting outside the hall.
They are Peter Teleborian
with him for questioning.
Why?
He is arrested on suspicion of serious
child pornography.
Specifically, possession of 8000
child pornography images and movies --
- Found in the computer.
It has been seized.
Are you kind enough to keep up with here?
After you sit.
Court was unable to assess
all information the last hour --
- But finds no reason to keep
Lisbeth Salander custody.
You are then free up
condemnation.
Are you sure
that you should not with the Millennium?
You can put me off
here at Folkungagatan.
You know that it is
thanks Mick, no?
Jo. But...
Yes.
- I shall be able to reach you.
- Catch me on mail.
Well.
Bye.
- Why did it like this?
- Justice prevailed.
- So now there is a party?
- Now there is a party.
- What is in now?
- Now it begins!
... suspected of murder, among other things.
The organization has worked
from this floor in Stockholm --
- Behind serious legal assaults
v Lisbeth Salander.
But the story begins in the 60s.
When the subject began to
monitor the nation's interests.
Formally, they never existed.
Evidence suggests that not even
Rigspolitichefen known to the group.
In the mid-70s recruited
Section of a Soviet spy...
Lisbeth is released
pending condemnation.
- Here.
- What?
It is the legacy of Zalachenko.
I do not want anything from the pig.
No, but you are of now.
So I need your signature
that you have received this.
It is securities 300,000 --
- Plus that the property in Gosseberga
is valued at 1.5 million.
I would not have anything to do with it.
Then there is this...
An abandoned brick use
outside Norrtälje.
Just why is valued at 150,000.
Okay.
Lay the dirt and give the money to
charity.
I think you need to read it through.
Afterwards, I can sell it for you.
Micke welcome.
- Pizza Bussola? After you.
- Thank you. Bye.
What is this shit?
You deserve to die
your pig.
- 118118th
- Yes, hello.
Give me number one
motorcycle club in Svavelsjö.
- Who is it?
- Are you interested in Niedermann?
I'm listening.
SOS Alarm.
Cop Killer Ronald Niederman is
at Skederyds brickyard in Norrtälje.
A motorcycle group will kill him.
They are heavily armed.
Am I disturbing you?
- I was lying in the bath.
- Yes, I see...
- Have you seen the news?
- No.
Ronald Niederman is dead. A gang
from Svavelsjö MC killed him.
Then the police came and took the whole bundle.
Thanks for everything.
Thank you.
Even you.
We talk.
- We talk.
- Absolutely.
Texts by: CAKEMANiA
And that's the way the cookie crumbles.